[
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first President of the United States?",
    "options": [
      "George Washington",
      "Abraham Lincoln",
      "Thomas Jefferson",
      "John Adams"
    ],
    "answer": "George Washington"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization built the pyramids in Egypt?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Egyptian",
      "Mesopotamian"
    ],
    "answer": "Egyptian"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who is known for discovering America in 1492?",
    "options": [
      "Christopher Columbus",
      "Marco Polo",
      "Amerigo Vespucci",
      "Ferdinand Magellan"
    ],
    "answer": "Christopher Columbus"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous leader said, 'I have a dream' during the Civil Rights Movement?",
    "options": [
      "Martin Luther King Jr.",
      "Malcolm X",
      "Rosa Parks",
      "Harriet Tubman"
    ],
    "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient wonder was located in the city of Babylon?",
    "options": [
      "Hanging Gardens",
      "Colossus of Rhodes",
      "Great Pyramid of Giza",
      "Statue of Zeus at Olympia"
    ],
    "answer": "Hanging Gardens"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous nurse during the Crimean War and is known as the 'Lady with the Lamp'?",
    "options": [
      "Florence Nightingale",
      "Clara Barton",
      "Mary Seacole",
      "Dorothea Dix"
    ],
    "answer": "Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Renaissance period begin?",
    "options": [
      "14th century",
      "16th century",
      "18th century",
      "20th century"
    ],
    "answer": "14th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the leader of the American Civil Rights Movement and won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964?",
    "options": [
      "Malcolm X",
      "Martin Luther King Jr.",
      "Rosa Parks",
      "Harriet Tubman"
    ],
    "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous pirate sailed the Caribbean Sea during the Golden Age of Piracy?",
    "options": [
      "Blackbeard",
      "Captain Kidd",
      "Anne Bonny",
      "Calico Jack"
    ],
    "answer": "Blackbeard"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean?",
    "options": [
      "Amelia Earhart",
      "Bessie Coleman",
      "Valentina Tereshkova",
      "Harriet Quimby"
    ],
    "answer": "Amelia Earhart"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization built the Great Wall of China?",
    "options": [
      "Mongols",
      "Japanese",
      "Chinese",
      "Koreans"
    ],
    "answer": "Chinese"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who wrote the 'Iliad' and the 'Odyssey' in ancient Greece?",
    "options": [
      "Homer",
      "Sophocles",
      "Aristotle",
      "Sappho"
    ],
    "answer": "Homer"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is known for creating the first system of writing called cuneiform?",
    "options": [
      "Sumerians",
      "Mayans",
      "Incas",
      "Aztecs"
    ],
    "answer": "Sumerians"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous queen of ancient Egypt known for her beauty and intelligence?",
    "options": [
      "Cleopatra",
      "Nefertiti",
      "Hatshepsut",
      "Isis"
    ],
    "answer": "Cleopatra"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which year did the Titanic sink after hitting an iceberg?",
    "options": [
      "1912",
      "1920",
      "1905",
      "1931"
    ],
    "answer": "1912"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the leader of the nonviolent movement for India's independence and is known as 'Mahatma'?",
    "options": [
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Subhas Chandra Bose",
      "Sardar Patel",
      "Mahatma Gandhi"
    ],
    "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization built the city of Troy, as mentioned in the 'Iliad'?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Trojan"
    ],
    "answer": "Trojan"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first woman to win a Nobel Prize and is famous for her work in radioactivity?",
    "options": [
      "Marie Curie",
      "Rosalind Franklin",
      "Ada Lovelace",
      "Barbara McClintock"
    ],
    "answer": "Marie Curie"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous scientist formulated the laws of motion and gravity?",
    "options": [
      "Isaac Newton",
      "Albert Einstein",
      "Galileo Galilei",
      "Nikola Tesla"
    ],
    "answer": "Isaac Newton"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first emperor of China and is known for the Terracotta Army?",
    "options": [
      "Emperor Qin Shi Huang",
      "Emperor Han Wudi",
      "Emperor Tang Taizong",
      "Emperor Wu Zetian"
    ],
    "answer": "Emperor Qin Shi Huang"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is credited with the invention of democracy?",
    "options": [
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Greek",
      "Egyptian"
    ],
    "answer": "Greek"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous nurse during the Crimean War and is known as the 'Lady with the Lamp'?",
    "options": [
      "Florence Nightingale",
      "Clara Barton",
      "Mary Seacole",
      "Dorothea Dix"
    ],
    "answer": "Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Renaissance period begin?",
    "options": [
      "14th century",
      "16th century",
      "18th century",
      "20th century"
    ],
    "answer": "14th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the leader of the American Civil Rights Movement and won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1964?",
    "options": [
      "Malcolm X",
      "Martin Luther King Jr.",
      "Rosa Parks",
      "Harriet Tubman"
    ],
    "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr."
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous pirate sailed the Caribbean Sea during the Golden Age of Piracy?",
    "options": [
      "Blackbeard",
      "Captain Kidd",
      "Anne Bonny",
      "Calico Jack"
    ],
    "answer": "Blackbeard"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean?",
    "options": [
      "Amelia Earhart",
      "Bessie Coleman",
      "Valentina Tereshkova",
      "Harriet Quimby"
    ],
    "answer": "Amelia Earhart"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization built the Great Wall of China?",
    "options": [
      "Mongols",
      "Japanese",
      "Chinese",
      "Koreans"
    ],
    "answer": "Chinese"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who wrote the 'Iliad' and the 'Odyssey' in ancient Greece?",
    "options": [
      "Homer",
      "Sophocles",
      "Aristotle",
      "Sappho"
    ],
    "answer": "Homer"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is known for creating the first system of writing called cuneiform?",
    "options": [
      "Sumerians",
      "Mayans",
      "Incas",
      "Aztecs"
    ],
    "answer": "Sumerians"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous queen of ancient Egypt known for her beauty and intelligence?",
    "options": [
      "Cleopatra",
      "Nefertiti",
      "Hatshepsut",
      "Isis"
    ],
    "answer": "Cleopatra"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which year did the Titanic sink after hitting an iceberg?",
    "options": [
      "1912",
      "1920",
      "1905",
      "1931"
    ],
    "answer": "1912"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the leader of the nonviolent movement for India's independence and is known as 'Mahatma'?",
    "options": [
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Subhas Chandra Bose",
      "Sardar Patel",
      "Mahatma Gandhi"
    ],
    "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization built the city of Troy, as mentioned in the 'Iliad'?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Trojan"
    ],
    "answer": "Trojan"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first woman to win a Nobel Prize and is famous for her work in radioactivity?",
    "options": [
      "Marie Curie",
      "Rosalind Franklin",
      "Ada Lovelace",
      "Barbara McClintock"
    ],
    "answer": "Marie Curie"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous scientist formulated the laws of motion and gravity?",
    "options": [
      "Isaac Newton",
      "Albert Einstein",
      "Galileo Galilei",
      "Nikola Tesla"
    ],
    "answer": "Isaac Newton"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first emperor of China and is known for the Terracotta Army?",
    "options": [
      "Emperor Qin Shi Huang",
      "Emperor Han Wudi",
      "Emperor Tang Taizong",
      "Emperor Wu Zetian"
    ],
    "answer": "Emperor Qin Shi Huang"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is credited with the invention of democracy?",
    "options": [
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Greek",
      "Egyptian"
    ],
    "answer": "Greek"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous nurse during the American Civil War and founded the American Red Cross?",
    "options": [
      "Florence Nightingale",
      "Clara Barton",
      "Mary Seacole",
      "Dorothea Dix"
    ],
    "answer": "Clara Barton"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for building the Colosseum in Rome?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Egyptian"
    ],
    "answer": "Roman"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous figure associated with the Underground Railroad, helping slaves escape to freedom?",
    "options": [
      "Harriet Tubman",
      "Frederick Douglass",
      "Sojourner Truth",
      "John Brown"
    ],
    "answer": "Harriet Tubman"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Industrial Revolution begin?",
    "options": [
      "18th century",
      "19th century",
      "20th century",
      "21st century"
    ],
    "answer": "18th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous Scottish queen known for her tragic life and conflict with Elizabeth I?",
    "options": [
      "Catherine de' Medici",
      "Anne Boleyn",
      "Mary, Queen of Scots",
      "Elizabeth Woodville"
    ],
    "answer": "Mary, Queen of Scots"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is known for creating the first Olympic Games?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Egyptian"
    ],
    "answer": "Greek"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first man to step onto the moon's surface during the Apollo 11 mission?",
    "options": [
      "Neil Armstrong",
      "Buzz Aldrin",
      "Yuri Gagarin",
      "Michael Collins"
    ],
    "answer": "Neil Armstrong"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for creating the Code of Hammurabi, one of the earliest written legal codes?",
    "options": [
      "Sumerians",
      "Babylonians",
      "Assyrians",
      "Hittites"
    ],
    "answer": "Babylonians"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous explorer who completed the first circumnavigation of the Earth?",
    "options": [
      "Christopher Columbus",
      "Ferdinand Magellan",
      "James Cook",
      "Vasco da Gama"
    ],
    "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the American Revolution take place?",
    "options": [
      "17th century",
      "18th century",
      "19th century",
      "20th century"
    ],
    "answer": "18th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the leader of the ancient Persian Empire during the Greco-Persian Wars?",
    "options": [
      "Darius I",
      "Cyrus the Great",
      "Xerxes I",
      "Artaxerxes I"
    ],
    "answer": "Xerxes I"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous figure is known for his contributions to the field of electricity and the invention of the lightning rod?",
    "options": [
      "Thomas Edison",
      "Nikola Tesla",
      "Benjamin Franklin",
      "Alexander Graham Bell"
    ],
    "answer": "Benjamin Franklin"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for constructing the city of Machu Picchu in the Andes Mountains?",
    "options": [
      "Mayans",
      "Aztecs",
      "Incas",
      "Moche"
    ],
    "answer": "Incas"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous nurse and social reformer known for her work during the Crimean War?",
    "options": [
      "Florence Nightingale",
      "Clara Barton",
      "Mary Seacole",
      "Dorothea Dix"
    ],
    "answer": "Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which ancient civilization did the philosopher Confucius live?",
    "options": [
      "Chinese",
      "Indian",
      "Greek",
      "Roman"
    ],
    "answer": "Chinese"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous Native American woman who played a key role in the Lewis and Clark expedition?",
    "options": [
      "Pocahontas",
      "Sacagawea",
      "Squanto",
      "Chief Joseph"
    ],
    "answer": "Sacagawea"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What was the ancient Egyptian writing system consisting of pictorial symbols?",
    "options": [
      "Cuneiform",
      "Hieroglyphics",
      "Runes",
      "Alphabet"
    ],
    "answer": "Hieroglyphics"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Greek philosopher known for his contributions to philosophy and teachings of his student, Alexander the Great?",
    "options": [
      "Socrates",
      "Aristotle",
      "Plato",
      "Heraclitus"
    ],
    "answer": "Aristotle"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Renaissance period reach its peak?",
    "options": [
      "14th century",
      "15th century",
      "16th century",
      "17th century"
    ],
    "answer": "16th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Roman general and statesman who played a crucial role in the events that led to the demise of the Roman Republic?",
    "options": [
      "Julius Caesar",
      "Augustus",
      "Cicero",
      "Hannibal"
    ],
    "answer": "Julius Caesar"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous explorer is credited with discovering the sea route from Europe to India?",
    "options": [
      "Christopher Columbus",
      "Ferdinand Magellan",
      "Vasco da Gama",
      "John Cabot"
    ],
    "answer": "Vasco da Gama"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous English nurse known as the 'Lady with the Lamp' during the Crimean War?",
    "options": [
      "Florence Nightingale",
      "Clara Barton",
      "Mary Seacole",
      "Dorothea Dix"
    ],
    "answer": "Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for creating the first system of writing using hieroglyphs?",
    "options": [
      "Sumerians",
      "Egyptians",
      "Mesoamericans",
      "Chinese"
    ],
    "answer": "Egyptians"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous queen of ancient Persia known for her bravery and role in saving her people?",
    "options": [
      "Cleopatra",
      "Nefertiti",
      "Hatshepsut",
      "Esther"
    ],
    "answer": "Esther"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which year did the United States declare its independence from Great Britain?",
    "options": [
      "1776",
      "1789",
      "1801",
      "1812"
    ],
    "answer": "1776"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous figure known for his theory of evolution by natural selection?",
    "options": [
      "Charles Darwin",
      "Gregor Mendel",
      "Louis Pasteur",
      "Alfred Russel Wallace"
    ],
    "answer": "Charles Darwin"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Egyptian queen famous for her relationships with Julius Caesar and Mark Antony?",
    "options": [
      "Nefertiti",
      "Hatshepsut",
      "Cleopatra",
      "Isis"
    ],
    "answer": "Cleopatra"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for building the city of Petra in Jordan?",
    "options": [
      "Persian",
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Nabataean"
    ],
    "answer": "Nabataean"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous Viking explorer and the first European to reach North America?",
    "options": [
      "Leif Erikson",
      "Erik the Red",
      "Harald Hardrada",
      "Ragnar Lothbrok"
    ],
    "answer": "Leif Erikson"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Black Death pandemic occur, causing widespread death in Europe?",
    "options": [
      "14th century",
      "15th century",
      "16th century",
      "17th century"
    ],
    "answer": "14th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the leader of the Indian independence movement and advocate of nonviolent civil disobedience?",
    "options": [
      "Jawaharlal Nehru",
      "Sardar Patel",
      "Subhas Chandra Bose",
      "Mahatma Gandhi"
    ],
    "answer": "Mahatma Gandhi"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is known for constructing the Terracotta Army in the mausoleum of their first emperor?",
    "options": [
      "Han",
      "Qin",
      "Shang",
      "Tang"
    ],
    "answer": "Qin"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous pirate known for his association with the Jolly Roger flag and the Golden Age of Piracy?",
    "options": [
      "Anne Bonny",
      "Blackbeard",
      "Calico Jack",
      "Captain Kidd"
    ],
    "answer": "Blackbeard"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did Joan of Arc play a significant role during the Hundred Years' War?",
    "options": [
      "12th century",
      "14th century",
      "15th century",
      "17th century"
    ],
    "answer": "15th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Greek philosopher known for his method of questioning, now called the Socratic method?",
    "options": [
      "Socrates",
      "Aristotle",
      "Plato",
      "Heraclitus"
    ],
    "answer": "Socrates"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for constructing the city of Machu Picchu in the Andes Mountains?",
    "options": [
      "Mayans",
      "Aztecs",
      "Incas",
      "Moche"
    ],
    "answer": "Incas"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous nurse and social reformer known for her work during the Crimean War?",
    "options": [
      "Florence Nightingale",
      "Clara Barton",
      "Mary Seacole",
      "Dorothea Dix"
    ],
    "answer": "Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which ancient civilization did the philosopher Confucius live?",
    "options": [
      "Chinese",
      "Indian",
      "Greek",
      "Roman"
    ],
    "answer": "Chinese"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous Native American woman who played a key role in the Lewis and Clark expedition?",
    "options": [
      "Pocahontas",
      "Sacagawea",
      "Squanto",
      "Chief Joseph"
    ],
    "answer": "Sacagawea"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What was the ancient Egyptian writing system consisting of pictorial symbols?",
    "options": [
      "Cuneiform",
      "Hieroglyphics",
      "Runes",
      "Alphabet"
    ],
    "answer": "Hieroglyphics"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Greek philosopher known for his contributions to philosophy and teachings of his student, Alexander the Great?",
    "options": [
      "Socrates",
      "Aristotle",
      "Plato",
      "Heraclitus"
    ],
    "answer": "Aristotle"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Renaissance period reach its peak?",
    "options": [
      "14th century",
      "15th century",
      "16th century",
      "17th century"
    ],
    "answer": "16th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Roman general and statesman who played a crucial role in the events that led to the demise of the Roman Republic?",
    "options": [
      "Julius Caesar",
      "Augustus",
      "Cicero",
      "Hannibal"
    ],
    "answer": "Julius Caesar"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous explorer is credited with discovering the sea route from Europe to India?",
    "options": [
      "Christopher Columbus",
      "Ferdinand Magellan",
      "Vasco da Gama",
      "John Cabot"
    ],
    "answer": "Vasco da Gama"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous English nurse known as the 'Lady with the Lamp' during the Crimean War?",
    "options": [
      "Florence Nightingale",
      "Clara Barton",
      "Mary Seacole",
      "Dorothea Dix"
    ],
    "answer": "Florence Nightingale"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for creating the first system of writing using hieroglyphs?",
    "options": [
      "Sumerians",
      "Egyptians",
      "Mesoamericans",
      "Chinese"
    ],
    "answer": "Egyptians"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous queen of ancient Persia known for her bravery and role in saving her people?",
    "options": [
      "Cleopatra",
      "Nefertiti",
      "Hatshepsut",
      "Esther"
    ],
    "answer": "Esther"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which year did the United States declare its independence from Great Britain?",
    "options": [
      "1776",
      "1789",
      "1801",
      "1812"
    ],
    "answer": "1776"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous figure known for his theory of evolution by natural selection?",
    "options": [
      "Charles Darwin",
      "Gregor Mendel",
      "Louis Pasteur",
      "Alfred Russel Wallace"
    ],
    "answer": "Charles Darwin"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is known for building the city of Troy, as mentioned in the 'Iliad'?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Trojan"
    ],
    "answer": "Trojan"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first woman to win a Nobel Prize and is famous for her work in radioactivity?",
    "options": [
      "Marie Curie",
      "Rosalind Franklin",
      "Ada Lovelace",
      "Barbara McClintock"
    ],
    "answer": "Marie Curie"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which famous scientist formulated the laws of motion and gravity?",
    "options": [
      "Isaac Newton",
      "Albert Einstein",
      "Galileo Galilei",
      "Nikola Tesla"
    ],
    "answer": "Isaac Newton"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the first emperor of China and is known for the Terracotta Army?",
    "options": [
      "Emperor Qin Shi Huang",
      "Emperor Han Wudi",
      "Emperor Tang Taizong",
      "Emperor Wu Zetian"
    ],
    "answer": "Emperor Qin Shi Huang"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is credited with the invention of democracy?",
    "options": [
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Greek",
      "Egyptian"
    ],
    "answer": "Greek"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Chinese philosopher known for his teachings on ethics and morality?",
    "options": [
      "Confucius",
      "Laozi",
      "Mencius",
      "Sun Tzu"
    ],
    "answer": "Confucius"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for creating the Rosetta Stone, which helped decipher Egyptian hieroglyphs?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Egyptian"
    ],
    "answer": "Egyptian"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous leader of the Soviet Union during World War II?",
    "options": [
      "Joseph Stalin",
      "Vladimir Lenin",
      "Leon Trotsky",
      "Mikhail Gorbachev"
    ],
    "answer": "Joseph Stalin"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Renaissance artist Leonardo da Vinci live?",
    "options": [
      "13th century",
      "15th century",
      "17th century",
      "19th century"
    ],
    "answer": "15th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Roman general who crossed the Alps with elephants during the Second Punic War?",
    "options": [
      "Julius Caesar",
      "Scipio Africanus",
      "Hannibal",
      "Augustus"
    ],
    "answer": "Hannibal"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for constructing Stonehenge in England?",
    "options": [
      "Celtic",
      "Anglo-Saxon",
      "Norse",
      "Neolithic"
    ],
    "answer": "Neolithic"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Greek mathematician known for his theorem in geometry?",
    "options": [
      "Euclid",
      "Pythagoras",
      "Archimedes",
      "Aristotle"
    ],
    "answer": "Euclid"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Industrial Revolution lead to significant changes in manufacturing and transportation?",
    "options": [
      "17th century",
      "18th century",
      "19th century",
      "20th century"
    ],
    "answer": "18th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Egyptian pharaoh famous for the construction of the Great Pyramid of Giza?",
    "options": [
      "Tutankhamun",
      "Cleopatra",
      "Ramesses II",
      "Khufu"
    ],
    "answer": "Khufu"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for the creation of the Hanging Gardens in the city of Babylon?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Mesopotamian"
    ],
    "answer": "Mesopotamian"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous explorer and navigator responsible for the first circumnavigation of the Earth?",
    "options": [
      "Christopher Columbus",
      "Ferdinand Magellan",
      "James Cook",
      "Vasco da Gama"
    ],
    "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the famous Gunpowder Plot, led by Guy Fawkes, take place in England?",
    "options": [
      "16th century",
      "17th century",
      "18th century",
      "19th century"
    ],
    "answer": "17th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Persian king who led the invasion of Greece during the Battle of Thermopylae?",
    "options": [
      "Darius I",
      "Xerxes I",
      "Cyrus the Great",
      "Artaxerxes I"
    ],
    "answer": "Xerxes I"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for the creation of the Code of Hammurabi, one of the earliest legal codes?",
    "options": [
      "Babylonians",
      "Assyrians",
      "Sumerians",
      "Persians"
    ],
    "answer": "Babylonians"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous English playwright and poet often referred to as the 'Bard of Avon'?",
    "options": [
      "William Shakespeare",
      "Christopher Marlowe",
      "John Milton",
      "Geoffrey Chaucer"
    ],
    "answer": "William Shakespeare"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the Renaissance period emerge in Italy?",
    "options": [
      "13th century",
      "14th century",
      "15th century",
      "16th century"
    ],
    "answer": "14th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Greek warrior and hero of the Trojan War known for his invulnerability?",
    "options": [
      "Achilles",
      "Odysseus",
      "Hector",
      "Ajax"
    ],
    "answer": "Achilles"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for the construction of the pyramids at Teotihuacan in present-day Mexico?",
    "options": [
      "Aztecs",
      "Mayans",
      "Olmecs",
      "Toltecs"
    ],
    "answer": "Aztecs"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the famous African-American abolitionist and former slave known for her work on the Underground Railroad?",
    "options": [
      "Frederick Douglass",
      "Harriet Tubman",
      "Sojourner Truth",
      "Nat Turner"
    ],
    "answer": "Harriet Tubman"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the famous Battle of Agincourt take place during the Hundred Years' War?",
    "options": [
      "12th century",
      "14th century",
      "15th century",
      "17th century"
    ],
    "answer": "15th century"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Roman general and statesman known for his military campaigns in Gaul and the crossing of the Rubicon?",
    "options": [
      "Julius Caesar",
      "Augustus",
      "Cicero",
      "Mark Antony"
    ],
    "answer": "Julius Caesar"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Which ancient civilization is known for the construction of the Parthenon in Athens?",
    "options": [
      "Greek",
      "Roman",
      "Persian",
      "Egyptian"
    ],
    "answer": "Greek"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the influential queen of England known for her reign during the Elizabethan era?",
    "options": [
      "Queen Victoria",
      "Queen Mary I",
      "Queen Elizabeth I",
      "Queen Anne"
    ],
    "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "What ancient civilization is known for the construction of the Great Sphinx of Giza?",
    "options": [
      "Sumerians",
      "Babylonians",
      "Egyptians",
      "Persians"
    ],
    "answer": "Egyptians"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "Who was the ancient Chinese military strategist and philosopher known for 'The Art of War'?",
    "options": [
      "Confucius",
      "Laozi",
      "Sun Tzu",
      "Mencius"
    ],
    "answer": "Sun Tzu"
  },
  {
    "category": "History",
    "question": "In which century did the famous Silk Road facilitate trade and cultural exchange between East and West?",
    "options": [
      "3rd century BC",
      "1st century AD",
      "5th century AD",
      "10th century AD"
    ],
    "answer": "1st century AD"
  }
]



